<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Umphlett</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Chris Umphlett</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Unstuck: Professionalism and Preparation</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-unstuck-professionalism-and-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/getting-unstuck-professionalism-and-preparation/</guid>
      <description>I am reading Matt Perman&amp;rsquo;s How to Get Unstuck and taking on the writing exercise at the end of each chapter. More information in this article on the introduction.
Chapters 9-10 are about being a professional and the importance of preparation. These were two of my favorite chapters so far as each expressed very well some things that I have thought before. It gave me language and organized processes that will help me to do some things that I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the past, but better and more focused and with more consistency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a car maintenance log and reminders with R and SQL Server</title>
      <link>/posts/creating-a-car-maintenance-log-and-reminders-with-r-and-sql-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/creating-a-car-maintenance-log-and-reminders-with-r-and-sql-server/</guid>
      <description>For years I used an Excel workbook with VBA to track our vehicles’ preventive maintenance and notify me when something was needed. This process hasn’t worked well the last couple years as the laptop with MS Office and the scheduled task is rarely left on when it is scheduled to run. I had also failed to account properly for some maintenace tasks that had never been done, but I intended to do, within a few years after purchasing the vehicles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Unstuck Chapters 7-8: The importance of vision and mission</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-unstuck-vision-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/getting-unstuck-vision-mission/</guid>
      <description>I am reading Matt Perman&amp;rsquo;s How to Get Unstuck and taking on the writing exercise at the end of each chapter. More information in this article on the introduction.
Part 2 of the book is on Personal Leadership, Perman&amp;rsquo;s all-encompassing term for what we need to do in order to get and stay unstuck. It is what is required in order to take the personal effectiveness of chapters 4-6 and direct it appropriately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic resume&#39;s built in R with the vitae package</title>
      <link>/posts/vitae-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/vitae-package/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago I came across the vitae package which was recently developed by Mitchell O’Hara Wild. I have been using the same basic resume template for over 10 years, mainly by default, but I really liked the layout offered by one of the vitae templates and the ability to build it with R Markdown turned a chore into something fun to do (keeping the resume current).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Unstuck Chapters 4-6: Personal Effectiveness</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-unstuck-personal-effectiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/getting-unstuck-personal-effectiveness/</guid>
      <description>I am reading Matt Perman&amp;rsquo;s How to Get Unstuck and taking on the writing exercise at the end of each chapter. More information in this article on the introduction.
Chapters 4 - 6 all discuss what Perman calls &amp;ldquo;Personal Effectiveness&amp;rdquo;. It is more than just time management:
 personal effectiveness is the skill of leading yourself every day to get the right things done in the right way, for the right reason, and in the shortest possible amount of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Monthly and YTD progress towards a target: the Glidepath Chart</title>
      <link>/posts/the-glidepath-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-glidepath-chart/</guid>
      <description>While I’d love to minimize the distinction made in business according to the idiosyncracies of the calendar, I believe it’s here to stay. We analysts have been spoiled by base 10. It is a bit of an annoyance to have time intervals that don’t fit neatly: 7 days make a week, but 4.23 weeks make a month? There are 12 months in a year but 365.25 days? Beyond that, why do we compare 28 day periods versus 31 day periods (Jan to Feb to March)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Unstuck: Ch 2 &amp; 3, What it means to be Unstuck</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-unstuck-ch-2-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/getting-unstuck-ch-2-3/</guid>
      <description>I am reading Matt Perman’s How to Get Unstuck and taking on the writing exercise at the end of each chapter. More information in this article on the introduction.
Chapters 2 and 3 describe what being unstuck looks like.
Chapter 2Perman defines being unstuck as &amp;gt; Getting important work done through obstacles, and to keep doing it over and over again.
If you are unstuck you will be using these skills: Clarity, Discipline, Focus, Energy, Speed, Estimation, Completion and Love for others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Unstuck: Ch 1, How We Get Stuck</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-unstuck-ch-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/getting-unstuck-ch-1/</guid>
      <description>I am reading Matt Perman&amp;rsquo;s How to Get Unstuck and taking on the writing exercise at the end of each chapter. More information in this article on the introduction.
Chapter 1 describes what Perman says are the three ways we get stuck: 1. We don&amp;rsquo;t know what God wants us to do 2. We know but we don&amp;rsquo;t know how to make it happen 3. Obstacles prevent us from doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Unstuck: Intro</title>
      <link>/posts/perman-unstuck-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/perman-unstuck-1/</guid>
      <description>I just began reading Matt Perman&amp;rsquo;s How To Get Unstuck: Breaking Free From Barriers To Your Productivity. I was pleasantly surprised by a section he added to the end of each chapter&amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;The Unstuck Clinic&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash; which summarizes the chapter, has an application exercise for the reader and provides resources for further reading.
 Too often my zeal for wanting to read more becomes an obstacle to reading well. Even when I started this book a few days ago, part of the time reading the introduction was also while serving as a jungle gym for a four-year-old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindergarten Data Science</title>
      <link>/posts/kindergarten-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/kindergarten-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Last year I taught a data science lesson to my daughter’s kindergarten class. I learned that they already practice data science: in the morning they would observe the weather, record it on the computer, and then look at a visualization of the weather so far in the month. Amazing! I was able to share with them how that same process (observe/collect data, clean data, analyze data, and visualize data) is what I do at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Undergrad Student Outcomes</title>
      <link>/posts/studentoutcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/studentoutcomes/</guid>
      <description>Project OverviewThis data set contains data on fictitious undergraduate students. It includes demographic information, performance and outcomes. I used R to analyze and visualize what is significantly correlated with, and potentially predictive of, undergraduate outcomes of gpa and staying in school (“Persistence”).
There were many questions I would have asked if I could have spoken to someone who knew the data. For example, did high school GPA always exist on a six point scale?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/now/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by nownownow.com.
updated 2019-02-21
Listed below are categories that show what I&amp;rsquo;m spending most of my time doing. Ultimately, I am attempting to align these with my current vision for my career: To live in the intersection of data science and behavioral economics/decision science&amp;ndash; to be a data-driven decision scientist.
Current projects  This web site with basic pages, with a combination of R Studio, R blogdown and Github pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibraryThing Reading Timeline</title>
      <link>/posts/librarything/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/librarything/</guid>
      <description>For many years I used a web site called Shelfari to track my reading and wish list. This was eventually swallowed by Amazon and merged with Goodreads. For reasons I cannot remember now I did not like Goodreads and ended up switching to a service called LibraryThing that created a conversion process to get the Shelfari data in there. I haven’t used it as faithfully as Shelfari and only recently started marking dates when I completed books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Current Resume
When I began my career in the analytics space in 2011 it seemed important to me to gain specific, specialized knowledge in certain areas. I had previously been a &amp;ldquo;jack-of-all-trades, master of none&amp;rdquo; kind of guy and that was not where I wanted to be professionally. Business analytics became that area of focus but after eight years I know now that once you gain a certain competency in data analytics you realize that they are innumerable subdomains; I am now, once again, somewhat of a jack-of-all-trades.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>