<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Text Mining on Chris Umphlett</title>
    <link>/tags/text-mining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Text Mining on Chris Umphlett</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/text-mining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My first R package: openEndedAnalyzeR</title>
      <link>/posts/my-first-r-package-openendedanalyzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-first-r-package-openendedanalyzer/</guid>
      <description>Recently I created my first R package and deployed it to GitHub. I developed it as part of my work at Consumers Energy, working with survey data frequently to help improve customer experience. Below is the vignette that I have created to document the basic usage of the package.
openEndedAnalyzeR enables fast, pre-packaged analysis of qualitative survey responses (“open-ended” or “verbatims”). It is built on the framework of the tidytext package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis of online screen capture reviews with R and tidytext</title>
      <link>/posts/sentiment-analysis-of-online-screen-capture-reviews-with-r-and-tidytext/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sentiment-analysis-of-online-screen-capture-reviews-with-r-and-tidytext/</guid>
      <description>Lately I’ve been doing a lot of text mining at work, analyzing the relationship between various qualitative responses on customer surveys to the quantitative responses. On a given survey we may have several qualitative responses and I’m also working towards developing a generalized exploratory text and sentiment analysis that we can use to better determine what should be manually reviewed by business SME’s.
In that vein I combined some of what I’ve been learning doing that with an analysis of customer reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>