<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Chris Umphlett</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Chris Umphlett</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Bingo for Kids (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/posts/travel-bingo-for-kids-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/travel-bingo-for-kids-part-1/</guid>
      <description>As a kid I spent a lot of time on road trips playing travel bingo. Recently I found some cards at a toy store while traveling with my own children and they enjoyed using them as well. I wanted the cards to work better for my kids, especially my three-year-old who can’t see that well out the window, so I decided to create my own before our next road trip a few weeks later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Feature Selection with R &amp; CART</title>
      <link>/posts/automatic-feature-selection-with-r-cart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/automatic-feature-selection-with-r-cart/</guid>
      <description>For a recent work project I had a statistical problem I had not dealt with before: multi-class classification. We have a system that can classify about 75% of phone calls, and I needed to classify the remainder into one of five types. The data also had what to me were many features (~300) and I wanted a way to dynamically select features as this classification would be performed weekly but the call data could change significantly from week-to-week and over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting data from the Accuweather API</title>
      <link>/posts/collecting-data-from-the-accuweather-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/collecting-data-from-the-accuweather-api/</guid>
      <description>I began collecting hourly and daily forecast and actual weather data from the Accuweather API in May 2019. The endgame will be to do analysis to discover the points at which the forecast accuracy degrades (eg, an hourly forecast gets significantly worse at 4 hours away; a daily forecast gets worse at 3 days away).
I have learned quite a bit about weather forecasting without studying it directly– it is discussed in depth in both Nate Silver’s book The Signal and the Noise and Michael Lewis’ (Audible only) book The Coming Storm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Leaders Musician Flipbook</title>
      <link>/posts/little-leaders-musician-flipbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/little-leaders-musician-flipbook/</guid>
      <description>For Women&amp;rsquo;s History Month 2019 my first-grade daughter and I did a project together to celebrate the musical artists featured in Vashti Harrison&amp;rsquo;s books Little Leaders and Little Dreamers. We created a flipbook with the xaringan package for R and RStudio.
Here is a link to the flipbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a car maintenance log and reminders with R and SQL Server</title>
      <link>/posts/creating-a-car-maintenance-log-and-reminders-with-r-and-sql-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/creating-a-car-maintenance-log-and-reminders-with-r-and-sql-server/</guid>
      <description>For years I used an Excel workbook with VBA to track our vehicles’ preventive maintenance and notify me when something was needed. This process hasn’t worked well the last couple years as the laptop with MS Office and the scheduled task is rarely left on when it is scheduled to run. I had also failed to account properly for some maintenace tasks that had never been done, but I intended to do, within a few years after purchasing the vehicles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic resume&#39;s built in R with the vitae package</title>
      <link>/posts/vitae-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/vitae-package/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago I came across the vitae package which was recently developed by Mitchell O’Hara Wild. I have been using the same basic resume template for over 10 years, mainly by default, but I really liked the layout offered by one of the vitae templates and the ability to build it with R Markdown turned a chore into something fun to do (keeping the resume current).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>